Finding Aid for Herbert C. and Louise C. Youtie papers, 1921-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Herbert C. Youtie
  - Miscellaneous & Oversize
    - John Chrysostom 15 (Box 5, Tube 2)
    - John Chrysostom 16 (Box 5, Tube 3)
- Louise C. Youtie, 1921-1980
  The Louise C. Youtie series, 1921 - 1980 (3 linear feet) consists of materials from her scholarly work with papyri for over six decades. Contents include correspondence regarding papyri translation and acquisition of materials, article drafts, transcriptions and notes, photographs and negatives of papyri, and some microfilm. File cards, notes and records from her desk are also part of this series. Materials include her work with P.Mich.Inv. 21 which resulted in the publication of The Michigan Medical Codex. The arrangement of materials, as they were received from the University of Michigan Papyrology Collection, has been retained.
  - RBR (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Magic Fever (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Magic Formulae (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography on magic (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Newsprint clippings (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Notecards (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Hanson, A, 1971
  - P.Koln.inv. 337 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - H.I. Bell (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - H. P. Kraus (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Duke Magazine, July-August 1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Tracing Paper (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Hanfmann, George M.A. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Gold Tablet from Carnervon, Wales (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - P.Mich.inv. 2754 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Medical papyri and authors (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Medical texts needing corrections (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - OISUPOS (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Loose material (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Re P.Mich.inv. 21 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Re medical papyri papers red to library group (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Scarborough, J. "The Preface of Dioscorides' Materia Medica (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Hanson, Ann lecture "Images of the Female Body in the Greek Medical (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Writers"
  - Ann Hanson translations "Hippocrates: Diseases of Young Girls" (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - A.Hanson Hippocrates (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Offprints of medical texts (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - P. Haun. III 47 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - O. Bodl., 1948 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - BLEPHARA and PIESMA (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - P. Mich. inv. 488 and 1455 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - P. Fay. 338 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - KAI BAPTITA BLEPHARA (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - ZPE offprint (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Notes for medical texts (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Loose notes (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - P.Corn.inv. 47 and P.Ryl. II 531 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Medical prescriptions (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - P. Princ. III 155 and P. Coll. Youtie 4 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Offprints P. Princ. III 155, O. Bodl. II and Le Monde Grec (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - P. Princ. III 155v and PIESMA in Galen (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - 3 Medical Prescriptions for Preaux Testschrift (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - List of medical texts and material for MPER XIII (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - P.Ryl. Greek Pap. 531, microfilm (Box 7)
  - P.Lond. II 189, microfilm (Box 7)
  - Microfilm (unlabeled) possibly of a dictionary, microfilm (Box 7)
  - P.Grenf. I 52 slides (Box 7)
  - P.Erl. 40 photographic negative (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous notes and correspondence, 1936-1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Coptic papyri (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Various transcription drafts (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Texts for ZPE (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Kelsey Museum transfer (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Loose notes (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - H.C. Youtie correspondence, 1932-1962 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Photographs and negatives (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - L. Koenen correspondence (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Notecards (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - P.Mich.inv. 21 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Photos of silver tablet (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - A. Gara article "Due Papiri Dalla Collezione Michigan" (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Notes on medical terminology (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - P.Mich.inv. 6981 photographs (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - P.Corn. 113a (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - P.Mich.inv. 2952 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Unpublished loans (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - P.Mich.inv. 87 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - P.Mich.inv. 21a (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - P.Mich.inv. 21b (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - P.Mich.inv. 21c (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - P.Mich.inv. 21d (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - P.Mich.inv. 21e (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - P.Mich.inv. 21f and 21g (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - P.Mich.inv. 21g manuscript and 21h-m (Box 8, Folder 16)